你在治疗中心的时间开心吗
Did you enjoy your time at the treatment centre?
如果你不坦白 你就会被带到那里去
Cos that's where you're headed if you don't confess.
我没有那么做
I didn't do it!
我又感觉到了 我没有变得狂暴
I feel it again! I'm not turning rabid.
-你害怕我 -我都认不出你了
- You're scared of me? - I don't even recognise you any more.
这就是真实的我
This is who I am.
我没法在他那样的时候看着他
I can't look at him when he's like that.
噢 上帝
Jesus Christ.
你在干嘛
What you doing?
我在找Simon 你看到他了吗
I'm looking for Simon. Have you seen him?
视频字幕由 SSK字幕组 制作发布
字幕只供学习 请勿做任何商业行为
敬请关注新浪微博@SSK字幕组
这就是你看到的第一个从坟墓里复活的人
That's the first person you saw rise from their grave?
我是Simon 我准备要跟随他了
It's Simon. I'm ready to follow him.
一切都需要来了了结了 Simon
It has to be done, Simon.
翻译：琪琪 bezero 呆毛 17 酥酥
你必须杀掉第一个复活的人
You must sacrifice the First Risen
在她复活的第12个月12日的12点
on the 12th hour of the 12th day of the 12th month.
第一个复活者必须被杀掉
The First Risen must be destroyed.
校对：17 慕斯
这样 第二次重生才得以实现
Only then can the second resurrection occur.
后期：hhjie
时间轴：阿黎
你们好 今天由我为你们服务 我是一个符合安全标准的半死症患者
Hello. I'll be your waitress today. I'm a fully compliant PDS sufferer.
过去的24小时之内我已经注射过神经抑制剂
I have been administered Neurotriptyline in the last 24 hours
总监：慕斯
并且不会进入狂暴状态
and will not enter a rabid state.
哦 哈哈 真是个好消息
Oh. Ha-ha. That's good to know.
茶还是咖啡
Tea or coffee?
咖啡吧 谢谢
Er... coffee, thanks.
什么都不想吃
Don't fancy anything?
离我们到达诺顿村 还有三个小时
Still got three hours ahead of us till we reach Roarton.
我是一个不吃早饭的人
I'm not a breakfast person.
噢 这是一日三餐中最重要的一餐
Oh, it's the most important meal of the day.
你会需要这一餐的
You're going to need it.
采集可不是一件容易事
Collections never go easy.
往往造成一场激战
Always put up a fight.
我不介意剩下的路我来开
I don't mind driving the rest of the way.
好吧 你会发现这是个错误选择
All right, it's your funeral.
到了12月12号 你们就都会知道那意味着什么
to 12th December, and you all know what that means.
诺顿村的冬祭表演就快要来了
Roarton Village's winter fête extravaganza is upon us.
怎么了 爸爸
What's going on, Dad?
我和你妈妈做了一个决定
Me and your mum have come to a decision.
-什么决定 -嗯
- A decision? - Mm.
我们觉得这个样子最好 万无一失
Yeah, we think it's best, all things considered,
让理事会 你知道的 做他们要做的事情
to let the council, you know, do what they're going to do.
你 你要让他们再把我带回诺福克
You... you're letting them send me back to Norfolk?
回到那个治疗中心
Going back to t'treatment
可能只是医生安排的
centre might be just what the doctor ordered.
他们接受过足够多的训练来应对这样的情况
They're trained up to handle situations like this.
他们能帮助你们变回原来正常的自己
They'll be able to help you get back to your normal self.
这就是正常的我
This is my normal self.
嗯 是时候听听专业意见了
Hm. It's time for a professional opinion.
所以 你 你就不再管我了么
So, you're... you're washing your hands of me?
不 我们在做我们确信能够让你收获最大利益的事
No. We're doing what we believe is in your best interests.
把我锁在我的卧室里 直到穿白色棉袄的男人
Locking me in my bedroom until the men in white coats
出现然后把我拖走吗
come along and drag me away?
那 那就是最大利益么
That... that's in my best interests?
对了 我不希望他们是把你拖走的
Well, I hope they won't have to drag you away.
至少 我可以打个电话给Amy吗
Can I call Amy, at least?
她也是那一伙的其中一员
She's part of the crowd
那已经对你造成了很不好的影响
that's been having a bad influence on you.
但是 我必须要跟她通话 爸爸 有些事情感觉不对劲了
Well, I need to speak to her, Dad. Something's not right.
我很担心她 爸爸
I'm worried about her, Dad.
你吃完早饭后可以下来开始你的尖锐批评 可以吗
You can come down for your shot after breakfast, ok?
爸爸
Dad!
Dad.
Jem 你准备好巡逻区域了吗
Jem? You getting ready to beat the bounds?
是的
Yeah.
我怎么了
What's happening to me?
我也不是很确定 Amy
I'm not entirely sure, Amy.
就好像是你的身体在觉醒
It seems like your body's waking up,
或是活过来
or coming alive,
或是那之类的事情
or something like that.
为什么是我
Why me?
我不知道
I don't know.
-可能是因为你比较特别 -特别
- Maybe you're special. - Special?
我奶奶经常说我很特别
My nan always said I was special,
但我设想那只是我奶奶说的
but I just figured that's something all nans say.
Philip 我要崩溃了
Philip, I'm freaking out.
嘿 嘿 嘿 没事的
Hey. Hey, hey. It's fine.
没事的 你很正常
It's all right. You're all right.
也许我们应该寻找一些这方面的合适的医嘱
Maybe we should get some proper medical advice on this.
去Russo那里看一下 你觉得如何
See Dr Russo. What do you think?
不 馊主意
No, bad idea.
你觉得会发生什么
What do you think would
如果我们告诉Russo医生我在改变
happen if we told Dr Russo I was... changing?
你觉得他会只轻拍我的背
Do you think he'd just pat me on the back,
给我一个棒棒糖 然后就让我走吗
give me a lolly and send me on my way?
他一定会通知治疗中心的
He'd call the treatment centre,
然后他们就会带走我 在我身上做实验
and then they'd cart me off to experiment on.
你知道那种生活是怎么样的
You know what the living are like.
你知道那些生活是怎么样的
You know what some of the living are like.
我们必须得保守这个秘密
Got to keep this under our hats.
好吧
Ok.
我们不能就这么待在这-为什么
- We can't just stay here. - Why?
我们会被冻死的
We'll die of hypothermia.
你冷嘛
You're cold?
你不冷嘛
Aren't you?
我都冻僵了
I'm freezing.
听 你听 我的牙齿都在打颤
Listen, listen. My teeth are chattering.
妈妈 别让他们带我去那
Mum, don't let them take me back.
Kier 综合考虑一切之后 只有这样最好
It's for the best, Kier, all things considered.
可是他们会把我当做抵抗者的 那就不好了
Not if they take me back as a non-compliant...
爸爸 我不会再干任何蠢事了 好嘛
Look, Dad, I'm not going to do anything stupid, ok?
你以前也这么说 但之后你就惹了大麻烦
You've said that before, then it all goes horribly wrong.
就这么定了 离开一段时间
No. Spending a bit of
待在Norfolk 会让你状态好很多
time in Norfolk will do you a tonne of good.
在那他们知道怎么对付你 对吧 Sue
They know how to take care of you there, don't they, Sue?
你睁眼瞎嘛
Open your eyes!
你知道让他们带我去治疗中心
You know what's going to happen to me
他们会如何对我
if they take me back to the treatment centre.
我要迟到了
I'm running late.
你会去参加活动纪念嘛
Are you coming to the fête, Steve?
我说过我会带Jem去游行 -好 待会见
- I've said I'll take Jem to t'march. - Ok, then.
Kier 我们晚一点回来给你送行
Kier, we'll be back later to see you off.
噢 那好吧
Oh. All right, then.
那行 Kier 回你的房间待着
All right, Kier, back to your room.
我能把这个带上去嘛
Can I take this up with me, Dad?
诺顿早报
Parish newsletter?
只是消磨时间用的
Reading material.
神爱世人 赐独子于凡尘
For He so loved the world, that He gave His one and only Son.
使信之者
Whoever shall believe in
不至灭亡 反得永生
him shall not perish but have eternal life.
引我避诱惑 救我离罪恶
Lead us not into temptation but deliver us from evil.
赐予我勇气 以终我宿命
Give me the courage to do my duty,
庇护我家园 免遭于灾难
to protect and defend my community from all harm.
帮帮我吧 上帝
So help me God.
Simon
Simon?
嗯
Yeah?
今天重生之时会是怎样的景象
When the dead rise today, what will they be like?
第二次重生 会
The Second Risen will be...
嗯 会发生一些变化
Well, they're going to change things.
将会终结
They're going to bring
苦难与迫害
an end to the suffering and the persecution.
第二次重生后
After the second Rising,
我们不会再被唾弃
we ain't going to be treated like dirt any more.
我们能帮忙嘛 Simon
Can we help you do it, Simon?
我必须独自完成一切
I've got to do this alone.
好吧 那我们要做什么 -做好心理准备
- Well, what should we do? - Prepare.
主啊 让信徒们完成今天的使命吧
Lord, let the disciple complete his mission today.
Martin小姐
Miss Martin.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
准备好了吗
Ready?
只要你开口 我就去清除威胁
To stop the threat. Just say the word.
谁是威胁
Who's the threat?
爱尔兰半死人 那个复生解放军极端分子
The Irish rotter. The ULA extremist.
别管他 队长
Leave it alone, Captain.
你说什么 他在策划袭击啊 Martin小姐
What you saying? He's planning an attack, Miss Martin.
你有证据嘛
Where's your proof?
证据 不是你告诉我的嘛 你叫我跟踪他
Proof? You said it yourself. You got me to follow him and...
但你什么也没发现
And nothing came of it.
不 不是的 我有所发现
No, that's not right. Something did come of it.
他进了旅馆 他见了另一个半死人
He went to that hotel. He met that other dead 'un.
我偷走了所有的证据 全都串起来了
I lifted the evidence off him. It all adds up.
如果我不逮捕他 他随时都会发起突袭
He's going to pounce any minute if I don't track him down and...
你想错了 队长
You are not thinking straight, Captain.
他不是个威胁
He is not a threat.
明白吗
Understand?
我没错 那个爱尔兰浑蛋需要人去阻止
I am thinking straight. That Irish rotter needs to be stopped.
回家去吧 Gary
Go home, Gary.
这是命令
That's an order.
别担心 Jem 你以后不会再见到我了
Don't worry, Jem. This is the last time you have to see me.
Jem 你至少也正眼看我一下
Jem, can you at least look at me?
开门
Open up!
打开这破门 不然我就硬闯了
Open this bloody door or I'll bust it through!
普天之下 莫非帝土
God's own country.
从Norfolk来的 不到四小时就到了吗
Norfolk? Under four hours?
真是好车技啊
That is impressive.
是啊 车开得超快
Yeah, it's quite the drive.
她现在还是方向盘手呢 哈
Her hands are still set at ten to two. Ha!
这里有医生嘛
Is there a doctor in the house?
希望我们不用再多跑几趟
Hopefully, we won't be making multiple trips.
很抱歉要带给你坏消息了
Well, sorry to be the bearer of bad news.
但我恐怕这是不可避免的
But I'm afraid it's just not possible.
如果你们给我电话 我还能提前告知你们
I'd have told you that over the phone, if you'd have called.
是啊 Tom 我能叫你Tom吗
Yeah, you see, Tom... Can I call you Tom?
你知道 Tom 你发来的测试十分有趣
You see, Tom, the tests you sent through were very interesting,
但想要深入了解的不止是我们
but it's not just us who needs to know.
还有Halperin&Weston公司
It's Halperin & Weston.
大公司难免强硬
Bit of a behemoth, bit of a juggernaut.
是啊 大公司 你不说我也知道
Big company. Don't need to remind me of that.
一旦Norfolk再次进行研究项目
Once the old ball starts rolling at Norfolk,
恐怕很难再阻止它进行下去了
it's nigh on impossible to stop the damn thing.
你在Norfolk学习过 对吧
You studied at Norfolk, correct?
确实很荣幸在那儿上过学
I had the privilege.
Tom 你知道
Well, Tom, you know,
如果你肯行个方便给我们地址
if you could do us the privilege of getting that address,
那可真是帮了大忙了
that would be a massive help.
对不起 我没有地址
I'm sorry. I don't have the address.
真的嘛 -暂时住址还是有的
- Really? - In between addresses, apparently.
那 那医疗记录上会有记录的对嘛
And... and the medical records would state that, would they?
你能给我们看嘛 不过看样子你也不打算给
If you were to show them to us, which you're not going to do.
我说过 我不能给你看病人的医疗记录
Like I said, I can't show you a patient's medical records.
嗯
Hm.
抱歉 本希望我能帮点什么
Sorry. Liked to have been of more help.
你也没办法啊 你又不知道Amy Dyer住哪
What can you do? You don't know where Amy Dyer lives.
对吧
Do you?
恐怕不知道
Afraid not.
我们再联系吧 Tom
We'll be in touch... Tom.
你还会喜欢我嘛
Are you still going to like me?
怎么了 -现在 我 嗯 变热了
- What? - Now I'm, er... warming up?
你只见过我半死的状态
You've only known me a bit deadly.
变热了可能你就不喜欢了
You might not like me heated up.
Amy
Amy.
你是冷是热我都喜欢
I'd like you cold. I'd like you hot.
你半冷不热我都喜欢
I'd even like you tepid.
无论你是生是死 你都是你
You're still you, dead or alive.
懂吗
All right?
怎么了 那条路是围栏的边界
What's wrong? That way's the perimeter fence.
今天有纪念重生的边界巡逻游行
Today's the Beating of the Bounds march.
最好避开点
Best avoid it.
爸爸 Kier之后会怎样
Dad, what's going to happen to Kier?
他得回治疗中心待上一段时间
He's going to go back to the treatment centre for a bit
那的人会帮助他恢复原来的样子
and they're going to help him get back to his old self.
他们不会把他关起来折磨虐待吧
They're not going to lock him up and do things to him, are they?
不 你怎么会这么想
No. Where did you get that idea?
他会没事的 Norfolk是个好地方
He'll be all right. Norfolk's a nice place to be.
我去边界巡逻了 他在屋里
Off to beat the bounds. He's in his room.
知道啦
Got you.
还不错
Not bad.
Amy 这是游行的终点
Amy, the march ends here.
我们就待一会儿 我只是想多摸摸别的东西
We won't be long. I just want to touch more things.
你有票的吧
You've got your ticket, haven't you?
是啊 我想在委员会里还是有点好处
Yeah. I suppose t'council were good for something.
Lamb夫人
Mrs Lamb.
议员 或者我该说 前议员
Councillor. Or should I say ex-councillor?
祝贺你得到议员提名
Congratulations on your nomination to the parish council.
也到时候了
It's about time this
镇子应该被敬畏神明的人民统治
village were represented by God-fearing folk,
而不是被一些浑浑噩噩的懦夫和肮脏的变态糟蹋
instead of just a bunch of flailing wimps and filthy perverts.
祝你今天过得愉快
Have a nice day.
等等
Hold your horses!
她不准进
She's not valid.
我给你票了 -你只给我了一张票
- I gave you my ticket. - You gave me a ticket.
她的票呢
Where's hers?
Lamb 如果你认真看了
Mrs Lamb, if you check the fine print on the fte charter,
我在职时起草的节日章程
a charter I helped draft while I was in office,
你会看到这么一条
you'll see a clause, and in that clause it states,
那就是 每张冬季节日票的持有者
that all ticket holders to
可以带一个伴侣入场
the winter fête are entitled to a plus-one.
Amy Dyer就是我的女伴
Amy Dyer's my plus-one.
新议员 我可以很明确的告诉你 她可以进去
I can assure you, Councillor Elect, she is valid.
边界巡逻游行在诺顿镇是一项古老的传统
Beating the bounds is an ancient tradition here in Roarton.
我很高兴大家都能来
I'm thrilled to see people turn out.
带这些真的有必要吗
Are all these really necessary?
大家有点热心过头了吧
I think everyone's going overboard.
我宣布Roarton的新围墙
I'm thrilled to announce the completion,
在预算内如期完成
under budget and on time,
今天就将剪彩
of Roarton's new perimeter fence.
如果没有委员会的新政策
We couldn't have achieved this construction
没有这项政策的保证
without the parish council adopting new policies
我们也做不出
that will guarantee the
保护我们社区安全的工程
safety of this community for generations to come.
都是多亏了你啊
We couldn't have done it without you,
-Martin小姐 -今天重点不在我
-Miss Martin. - Today isn't about me.
重点在我们大家 着手于新的开始 新的光明
It's about all of us, embarking on a new beginning, a new dawn,
安全 自豪 廉洁
protected, proud and incorruptible.
现在 该剪开这条彩带了 好让我们开始游行
Now... I should cut this ribbon so we can get a move on, eh?
谁有利器借我用一下吗
Anyone got a sharp implement I can use?
用这个 夫人
Here you are, missus.
谢谢
Thank you.
开始游行吧
So, let the march commence!
走吧
Come on, then.
这白痴又来了
Here comes dickhead.
-嗨 -哈喽
- 'Ey up. - 'Ey up.
-你可以走了 -啊
- Go on, then. Be off with you. - What?
我是来代替你的 笨蛋
I'm relieving you of your post, you tart.
我应该在这站岗一天的啊
I'm supposed to be on guard duty all day.
我调了 这样你就能休息一天了
I've fiddled it. Thought you could do with t'day off.
去庆祝吧 请你喝一杯热葡萄酒
Go to t'fête. Have a mulled wine on me.
快去 过了这村可就没这店了
Go on, then, before I see sense.
谢谢 Gaz 你真好
Ta, Gaz. You're all right.
谢您嘞 伙计
Cheers, pal.
你要去哪 你个废柴
You going somewhere, dry rot?
Simon在哪
Where's Simon?
-他去哪了 -我不知道
- Where is he? - I don't know.
说谎 你和你的小情人可是好得很呢
Bullshit. You and lover boy are like that.
Gary 我都好几天没看到他了
I haven't seen him for days, Gary.
你知道他在策划一场袭击的吧
You know he's planning an attack, don't you?
我不知道
No.
他妈的就是今天 我都搞清楚了
He fucking is. Today. I've sussed it out.
这是他行动地点的安好吗
Is this the code for where he's going to do it?
"死者将重生为不朽" 这是圣经里的话
"The dead shall rise again incorruptible." It's a Bible quote.
我知道 你个混蛋
I know that, you cheeky bastard.
你们全都认为我只是一个笨蛋 不是么
You know, all of you think I'm just some dumb grunt, don't you?
Gary 我不这么认为啊
I don't think you're dumb, Gary.
我只是觉得
I just think you're like
你就像其他人一样 偏执还妄想
everyone else around here, paranoid and delusional.
你们这群僵尸到处走动怎么能不多想
Is it any wonder with you ghouls walking about?
你知道吗 我爸爸说过
You know, my pap used to
世上原本是没有怪物的
say there were no such thing as monsters.
你们这群怪物出现了 就把世界弄得乌烟瘴气
Then you horror shows turn up and start tearing the world apart.
谁能来解决 我 只有我
And who's expected to deal with it, eh? Me, that's who.
你以为我愿意战斗吗
You think I wanted to fight?
你以为我愿意看见这些吗
Do you think I wanted to see the things I saw?
Gary 正在兴头上吧
You get off on all that shit, Gary.
在你们出现之前
I were ready to settle
我已经准备金盆洗手了
down before you fucking dead-heads turn up.
而现在 我和你妹妹
Then me and your sister had
却不得不管这些破事
to strap on the brass and take care of business.
因为 如果我们不管 就会死人 就死在我们的怀里
Cos if we didn't, people died. In our arms, no less.
不会再发生了
That's not going to happen again.
我不会让它再发生
I won't allow it.
我最后问你一遍
So, I'm going to ask you for the last time.
爱尔兰半死人在哪
Where's that Irish rotter?
中尉 接下来
Lieutenant. Think you can
你来带领游行的队伍好吗
handle leading the march the rest of the way?
不是队长带领吗
But shouldn't the Captain lead?
他不是不在嘛 就由你带吧
Well, he's not here, is he? Falls to you to take the reins.
-只要一个焦糖苹果 -我找给你零钱
- Just one toffee apple, please. - I'll just get your change.
-Sue 还好吧 -嗨 Shirley
- All right, Sue? - Oh. Hi, Shirley.
你都还好吧
You all right?
还好 我为Philip操心的都快长溃疡了
Aye, suppose. Philip's got me sprouting ulcers.
他怎么让你这么操心啊
Is he giving you a hard time?
你知道 这些小孩
Well, you know what they're like.
他们到了这个年纪 就感觉像变了个人
They get to a certain age, they become unrecognisable.
Kieren怎么样啊
How's Kieren holding up?
嗯 他也有点不好管了
Yeah. He's, er... being a bit difficult.
议会威胁他的方法真的太恶心了
Disgusting what the council's threatening to do with him.
好在他有你的支持
Good job he's got you to fight his corner.
Philip看起来很好啊
Your Philip looks like he's having a good time.
那是Amy Dyer么 她要哪个焦糖苹果干嘛
Is that Amy Dyer? What's she doing with that toffee apple?
竟然吃了
Eating it.
天啊 没有人在谋划袭击 Gary
Oh, Jesus Christ. No-one's planning anything, Gary!
是么
Yeah, right
你的鬼话能信吗
And I play for United
你有病吧
What is wrong with you?!
如果Jem现在看到你这样 天啊
If Jem could see you now. My God!
你简直一团糟 要崩溃了
You're a mess. You're coming apart at the seams.
卧槽 蓝色风暴
Fuck me. Blue Oblivion.
原来是你 一直都是你
It's you. It's been you all along.
那不是我的 我在Amy家发现的
Yeah, those aren't mine. I found them at the bungalow.
远在天边近在眼前啊
Hiding in plain sight.
你准备在哪儿用啊
Where were you planning on taking 'em?
军队 镇委员会大厅
Legion? Village hall?
还是在节日欢庆上用 准备在孩子们面前变狂暴吗
Fête? Going to go rabid in front of a bunch of kiddies, are you?
变态 混蛋
Sick bastard!
你不如现在就招了 你完蛋了
You may as well start singing now, cos you're fucked!
我已经要被送回治疗中心了
I'm already on my way back to the treatment centre.
你威胁不了我的
There's nothing you can threaten me with.
治疗中心 简直就是僵尸大聚会
Treatment centre? Dead-head holiday camp, more like.
你别想这么简单就离开 混蛋
Oh, no, you're not getting off that easy, rotter.
你想要变狂暴 好啊 我成全你
You want to go rabid? All right, let's go rabid.
重生 重生
Rise. Rise.
哇 真像那么回事
Ooh. Got the likeness down pat.
下次你可以画个红字在他的胸口
Next you can paint a scarlet letter on that one's chest.
Philip 给我赢只小老虎
Philip, win me the tiger, tiger.
真棒
Yes!
我拿到了
Hey, I got it.
看到了吧 我说过 会给你赢到手的
See? Told you I'd win you something.
你真好
That is so sweet.
-你好 Philip -妈
-Hello, Philip. - Mum.
嗨 你最近怎么样啊 亲爱的
Hi, love. How you doing?
我很好 谢谢 Wilson女士
I'm... I'm good, thanks, Mrs Wilson.
你确定没事吗 宝贝
You sure you're all right, sweetheart?
我刚才看到你在吃焦糖苹果
I... I saw you munching on a toffee apple just now.
嗯
Oh.
对
Oh, yeah.
我都忘了 我是半死症患者
I forgot. I'm PDS.
对啊
Course.
我不吃东西的
I don't eat. Whoops.
亲爱的 你还行吗
Oh, dear. You all right?
妈 我们出去一下
Better get some air, Mum.
嗯 Philip
Um... Philip?
你做的很好
You've done good.
谢谢 妈
Thanks, Mum.
重生 重生
Rise. Rise.
游行的队伍来了
The march.
快来
Come on.
不能让他们进来
We can't let them inside!
这特么是搞什么
What the hell is all this?
Gary 现在是展示你真正面目的时候了
Gary! Time to show 'em who you really are.
不
No!
下三滥永远都是下三滥
A rotter is a rotter!
嗑药还是不嗑药都一样
Drugs or no drugs!
－活人不许进入我们的圣地 －滚出去
- No living allowed on sacred ground. - Get out!
－人渣 －滚粗
- Scum! - Get out!
我来处理
I've got this!
我们就是不走 你们这些有脉搏跳动的贱种
We ain't moving, pulse-beater.
－你真的要挑起战争 －对
- You really want a war? - Yeah, we do.
你们在人数上完全不及我们
You're outnumbered.
一会儿你就知道 你们才是寡不敌众的那方
You're the one who's going to be outnumbered in a minute.
重生
Rise!
Rise! Rise!
重生
Rise! Rise! Rise!
Rise! Rise!
重生
是时候起床了 我的小兄弟
Time to wake up, little brother.
重生
Rise! Rise! Rise!
Jem 能听到么
Jem, you copy?
重生
Rise! Rise! Rise!
Gary 你在哪
Gary, where are you?
你哥吃了那颗蓝色风暴
Your brother's taken a shit-load of Blue Oblivion.
他现在在新的墓地那边
He's in the new graveyard right now.
重生
Rise! Rise! Rise!
我 我该干什么
What... what do I do?
Gary
Gary?
重生
Rise! Rise! Rise!
N重生
重生
Rise! Rise! Rise!
－重生 －待在那儿
- Rise! Rise! Rise! - Stay here.
重生
Rise!
闪开
Move.
Kieren
Kieren?
Kieren!
爸爸 快走开 你不应该看见这些的
Dad, go away. You shouldn't have to see this.
为什么 儿子
Why, son?
儿子 你能听见我说话么
Can you hear me, son?
爸 你在干嘛
Dad, what are you doing?
他不会伤害任何人的 他认识我 他能认出我
He's not going to hurt anyone. He knows me. He knows me.
他正在抗拒狂暴
He's fighting it.
你现在需要赶紧离开
You need to get out of the way right now.
他没有变 我知道他的理智还在
He's not gone. I know he's in there.
我一直相信你能听见我说话 kier
I've got to believe you can hear me, Kier.
我知道我们最近一直有很多不和
I know we haven't seen eye to eye lately.
但我仍然爱你了 我不在乎你变成什么样
That doesn't mean I don't love you, no matter what you are.
我现在知道我错了
I was wrong but I know now.
我不会让他们把你带走的 你是我的儿子 永远都是
I won't let 'em take you away. You're my son.
啊
Ah.
抓到你了
Got you.
爸爸
Dad!
快醒来吧 Danny
Wake up, Danny.
求求你了 Danny
Come on, Danny.
求你了
Please.
Amy 你要带我见谁
Who am I meeting, Amy?
嘿
Hey.
没事的 你没事了
It's all right. You're all right.
－我 我刚刚有伤着人么 －没有
- Did I... did I hurt anyone? - No.
你没有 你战胜了狂暴
No, you didn't. You beat it.
好
Ok.
站起来 我们走吧
Let's get you up. Let's go.
没事吧
Ok?
没事的 没事
It's ok, it's ok.
Simon 第二波重生
Simon, the second Rising...
不会发生了
It's not happening.
那怎么可以
But it's got to happen!
二次重生必须要完成
The second Rising has to happen!
额 我的爱好就是这些
And, um... that's about it for my hobbies.
他也是一个非常棒的运动员 奶奶
He's also a very good sportsman, Nan.
－Amy 你这样讲我多不好意思 －喔 这么羞射啊
- Amy, you're embarrassing me. - Aw, so modest.
你还好么
Are you ok?
我觉得
I... I think...
我觉得我的心脏
I think my heart...
正在跳呢
It's beating.
Amy Dyer
Amy Dyer!
你是第一个也是最后一个重生之人
You are the first and the last.
哦
Oh!
－你想让我怎么处理这些 －锁起来吧
- What you want me to do with these? - Lock up after.
我必须去阻止他们带走kieren
I've got to stop them taking Kieren.
他刚刚变狂暴了 Pearl开枪打了他
He just went rabid. Pearl shot him.
但是Simon为他挡住了那一枪
Simon took the bullet.
发生了什么
What's happened?
怎么了
What?
我从来没见过有人能抵挡蓝色风暴的药效
I've never seen anyone fight against Blue Oblivion before.
嗯哼 你若能长命百岁 什么样的都能见到
Well, if you live long enough, you'll see all sorts.
你真是个奇迹 Kieren
You're incredible, Kieren.
不 我不是
No, I'm not.
我 我只是不想再伤害别人了
I... I'm just a person who didn't want to do any more harm.
别把我说的这么玄乎 好么
Don't start getting all mystical on me, ok?
我不是救世主
I'm not the Messiah.
也没有超能力
I don't have any special powers...
不像某人
... unlike some people.
我也没有超能力
Well, I don't have any special powers.
你有隐形的能力
You have the power to disappear.
你突然走了 我掘地三尺也没有找到你 你去哪里了
You left. I searched everywhere for you. Where did you go?
进城了
The city.
为什么
Why?
救命 来人救命啊
Help! Someone help!
Amy
Amy?
大家注意
Excuse me.
听我说
都特么的给我安静下来
Excuse me!
我有一个消息
I... have a message of hope
要告诉你们
for all of you.
我们可以
We can...
我们可以战胜我们现在最大的敌人
we can conquer our greatest enemy today.
我们可以战胜死亡
We can conquer death.
什么
What?
我弟弟年幼时就在这儿死了
My brother died here when he was very young.
那是一次意外 他们说那是我
It was an accident. They said it was my...
总之是起事故
It was an accident.
他本不应该 他摔倒了
He shouldn't have been... He fell.
所有的 我们所做的一切错事都能够一笔勾销
All the... the terrible things we've done can be wiped clean.
一切重新开始
A fresh start.
不再悲伤
No more grief.
不再内疚
No more guilt.
只需等待二次重生
And all that needs to happen is the second Rising.
我知道我说过我不希望再有一次重生
I know I said I didn't want
但是二次重生和一次重生不一样
another one but it won't be like the first Rising.
二次重生将会带回善良和正直的人
The second Rising will bring back the good and... and righteous.
他们会毫发无损的回来
They'll come back whole
纯洁善良 一如从前
and... and pure
一切都会变的更好 大有改观
and everything will be better, so much better.
我可以向你们保证
I can promise you that.
我的弟弟
My little brother...
被深埋地下
... is in the ground.
冰冷
Cold...
并且孤独
... and alone.
他不应该待在那儿
He doesn't deserve to be there.
他应该从土里出来和我待在一起
He deserves to be up here with me.
重获新生 完好无缺
Alive and well.
想要获得二次重生
The second Rising will happen
需要牺牲第一个重生者
when the First Risen is sacrificed.
那个门徒原本 原本是要完成这项任务的
The disciple was meant... he was meant to do it.
可他没有 我 我以为是那个女孩
He didn't. I... I thought it was the girl.
我杀了她 但是什么都没有发生
I took care of her, and nothing. Nothing.
什么都没改变
Still nothing.
我 呃
I, er...
镇上的某个半死者一定是第一个重生的
One of the undead in this village must be the First Risen,
我要求你们和我一起
and I am asking you to join with me
翻遍所有角落把他找出来
in leaving no stone unturned.
镇上所有半死症患者都应被处决
Every PDS sufferer in Roarton must be destroyed.
刻不容缓
Right now.
住手
Stop it!
-她疯了         -你说的真对
- She's tapped. - You're right there.
我们当时在墓地里 然后Martin小姐走过来
We were at the graveyard and Miss Martin comes up to us
-说一些关于
- and says something about
Amy是第一个也是最后一个什么的  -噢 天哪
Amy being the first and the last. - Oh! Aah!
-接着Maxine刺伤了她 -她竟然在流血
- And then Maxine just stabbed her. - She's bleeding.
-你赶快做点什么 -我不明白
- You've got to do something. - I don't understand.
-Amy 不要啊
Amy, please.
噢
Oh!
不要啊 Amy
Please, Amy.
你不可以就这样离开我们
You're not allowed to leave like this.
你是我永远最好的朋友 知道么 永远最好的
You're my best dead friend for ever. Ok? Forever.
你 你一定要做到
That is... that is non-negotiable.
噢 噢
Oh! Oh!
-她失血过多了 -请你救救她
- She's lost too much blood. - You've got to do something.
她的瞳孔放大了
Her pupils have changed.
你站着干什么
What are you doing?
她死了
She's gone.
不
No.
不会的 她才不会死的
No, she's not.
你的衣服呢
Where's your outfit?
在我房间里
It's in my room.
葬礼上所有人都得穿时髦漂亮的衣服
Everyone at the funeral has to wear classy, more-geous outfits.
不能穿死板的黑色西装和裙子
No boring black suits or dresses.
这是她所要的超级酷的送别
It's part of her "Totally cool send-off".
我不知道我是不是应该去
I don't even know if I should be going.
当然 你要去 你可是在贵宾名单上
Yes, you should. You're on the VIP guest list.
好吧
Ok.
可他不能来
He's not invited.
我们分手了 我甩了他
We broke up. I broke up with him.
如果他和你是对立的 我会选择你这边
If it's his word against yours, then I choose yours.
我听说Maxine Martin被送去精神病院了
I heard Maxine Martin's been committed.
谢谢
Thanks.
-Philip在哪儿 -他不肯离开她的墓地
- Where's Philip? - He won't leave her graveside.
人总要有些念想的
You've got to have faith.
是啊
Yeah.
我这辈子不会给他们投票了
I am never voting for them again.
就该这样 噢 我们打算就这么玩 对吗
That's it. Oh, we're going to play it like that, are we?
对啊 好吧
Right. Ok.
我不知道你们还可以喝东西
I didn't know your kind could drink liquids.
是不能 只是喝点下去别人就会感觉轻松点
We can't. Just getting 'em in so people feel comfortable.
噢 亲爱的 你阵体贴
Oh, that's very considerate of you, love.
那些针眼瞳孔
Those pinprick eyes.
-让我觉得都快吐了 -噢
- I were almost sick in me mouth. - Ooh.
我真不敢相信Pearl会让那些家伙进来
I can't believe Pearl lets those things in here.
她只是心怀愧疚
She only does it out of guilt.
我才不管发生了什么 废物
I don't care what happened. A rotter...
-永远是废物 -你说对了 亲爱的
- Is a rotter. - You said it, love.
那些活人真恶心 我都想把胆汁吐出来了
The living make me want to puke black bile.
活人渣
Pulse-beating scum.
我想我们也只能做二等公民了
I guess we're stuck here existing next to them.
这种日子不会太长了
Not for long.
你从先知那儿听到的
You heard from the Prophet?
他说了什么
What did he say?
Simon是叛徒
Simon's a traitor.
那么第二次重生呢
What about the second Rising?
第一个重生的人还活着
The First Risen's still out there.
-嘿 -嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
这是你的吗
Is this yours?
曾经是 Gary送给我的
Used to be. Present from Gary.
-他从哪里弄的 -他给我做的
- How did he get it? - He made it for me.
不是的 Jem
No, Jem.
这个手链是Henry Lonsdale给你做的
Henry Lonsdale made this bracelet for you.
他在他消失的那晚还给我看的
He showed it to me the night he disappeared.
你知道他出了什么事吗 Jem
Do you know what happened to him, Jem?
那 那只是个意外
It... it was an accident.
那晚很黑 我在树林里夜巡 我
It was dark, I was on patrol in the woods, and I...
我以为他是个狂暴丧尸
I thought he was rabid.
那你想怎么做 Jem
What do you want to do, Jem?
我想我需要点帮助 Kier
I think I need some help, Kier.
好 好吧
Ok. Ok.
我们会给你帮助的
Let's get you some help, then.
去见一下我的父母
Come and see Mum and Dad.
算了吧
No.
他们认为是我的错
They blame me.
-不 他们不会 -如果Amy没有跟我一起回来
- No, they don't. - If Amy hadn't have come back here with me...
不 这不是你的错
No, it wasn't your fault.
Maxine Martin因为一些疯狂的念头 杀了她
Maxine Martin killed her over some... insane belief.
呵
Hm.
葬礼结束后 我们就该走了
After this, we should go.
走 去哪儿
Go? Go where?
离开这块地方
Away from here.
这里一点都不安全 Kieren
It's not safe, Kieren.
我不能走
I can't leave.
-你不是一直想要离开吗 -是的 原本是
- Isn't leaving what you wanted to do? - Yeah, it was.
Amy曾经问我
Amy once asked me
我要走多远才能接受自己
how many miles I'd have to go before I could be ok with myself.
我本来想可能我得走遍全世界
I thought I'd have to go around the whole world.
但是我现在不那么想了
And I don't think that any more.
我在这儿活得不错
I'm ok here.
好吧
Ok.
Simon
Simon.
我要感谢你
I wanted to thank you.
-感谢我什么 -你救了Kier
- Thank me? - You saved Kier's life.
本能反应罢了
Reflex.
你有住的地方吗
Have you got somewhere to stay?
是的 有 我 我暂时住在
Yeah. Yeah, I'm... I'm staying
Amy的小屋里 所以
up at Amy's bungalow at the moment, so...
你不准备走吧
Not going away, I hope?
不
No.
不 我会留在这儿
No, I'm staying put.
终于走了
Finally.
还有时间吗
Is there still time?
还有时间
There's still time.
把它装起来
Bag it.